Finding Aid for Ann Bradford Cook papers, ca. 1914, 1980
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ann Bradford Cook papers ca. 1914, 1980
Ann Bradford Cook
0.25 linear feet
2014021 Aa2
Photographs and printed material regarding the Martha Cook building on the University of Michigan campus, from Ann Cook, grandniece of benefactor William W. Cook.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The Cook papers were donated by Margaret Leary in 2014 ( 11074 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
Ann Bradford Cook was born in Ann Arbor on May 17, 1924. She received her A.B. From the University of Michigan in 1945 and a second degree in Home Economics from Wayne University in 1951. For most of her career Cook served as a dietician at Harper Hospital in Detroit. She was an active member of the Detroit Garden Club and served several terms on the Board of Governors of the Martha Cook Building, a women's dormitory at the University of Michigan. Cook died January 13, 2014.
Cook was the granddaughter of Chauncey Ferris Cook, a brother of William W. Cook a graduate from the University of Michigan Law School in 1882 and a major benefactor who donated the Martha Cook dormitory and much of the Law Quad. She grew up in the same house where William W. Cook was raised in Hillsdale, Michigan, and owned many items that had been in the house, including materials about the Martha Cook Building at the University of Michigan.
The Ann Cook records consist of two series: Printed Materials and Photographs. The Printed Materials include a book written by Olive Chernow, director of Martha Cook Building from 1973-1979, and a news clipping about the building.
The Photographs series includes various photographs of the interior and exterior of the Martha Cook Building, during and after construction. Photographers include the George R. Fuller Company, Daines and Nickel, and A. B. Bogart. Photographs are arranged by photographer or size, and the box listing provides a description of each photograph.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Martha Cook building.; University of Michigan--Student housing.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Cook, Ann Bradford.; University of Michigan. Martha Cook building.; University of Michigan--Student housing.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Printed Materials
  - Chernow, Olive,My Years at the Martha Cook Building, 1973-1979 (Box 1)
  - News Clippings, 1915 (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - 6.5x9" Photographs
    - Gold room (Box 1)
  - 7.5x9.5" Photographs
    - Gold room (Box 1)
    - Red Room showing portrait of Martha Cook (Box 1)
    - Exterior from west, with Samuel Parsons' garden in foreground (Box 1)
    - First floor entry hall; four chairs and Venus (Box 1)
    - Front entrance with Portia present (Box 1)
  - 11x14" Photographs
    - Gold room (Box 1)
    - Red Room (?) (Box 1)
  - George R. Fuller Co. Photographs
    - Pile of bricks in foreground, August 4, 1914 (Box 1)
    - Foundations in, September 1, 1914 (Box 1)
    - Steel frame, brickwork on exterior, October 1, 1914 (Box 1)
    - View along Tappan, west facade, completed exterior, September 1, 1915